YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 6. Program: Series V. Program Subjects
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES V. PROGRAM SUBJECTS
  - Subseries B. Health and Recreation
    - Programs and Projects
      - Sports and Fitness
        - YWCA of the USA/Nike Sports and Fitness Project
          - "New Face of Fitness" Fitness Training Program
            - New Jersey
              - Bergen County, 1996-97 (Box 615, Folder 26)
              - Princeton, 1996-97 (Box 615, Folder 27)
              - Trenton, 1995-97 (Box 615, Folder 28)
            - New York
              - Niagara (Lockport), 1996-97 (Box 615, Folder 29)
              - Schenectady, 1995-96 (Box 616, Folder 1)
              - Western New York (Buffalo), 1995-96 (Box 616, Folder 2)
            - North Carolina: Asheville, 1995-97 (Box 616, Folder 3)
            - Ohio
              - Cincinnati, 1995-96 (Box 616, Folder 4)
              - Cleveland, 1995-97 (Box 616, Folder 5)
              - Columbus, 1995-97 (Box 616, Folder 6)
              - Summit County (Akron), 1995-97 (Box 616, Folder 7)
            - Oklahoma: Oklahoma City, 1996-97 (Box 616, Folder 8)
            - Oregon
              - Portland, 1995-97 (Box 616, Folder 9)
              - Salem, 1995-97 (Box 616, Folder 10)
            - Pennsylvania
              - Carlisle, 1995-96 (Box 616, Folder 11)
              - Germantown-Philadelphia, 1995-97 (Box 616, Folder 12)
              - Gettysburg and Adams County, 1995-96 (Box 616, Folder 13)
              - McKeesport, 1996 (Box 616, Folder 14)
            - South Carolina: Greenville, 1995-97 (Box 616, Folder 15)
            - South Dakota: Sioux Falls, 1995-96 (Box 616, Folder 16)
            - Texas
              - Dallas, 1995-97 (Box 616, Folder 17)
              - El Paso del Norte Region, 1995-97 (Box 616, Folder 18)
              - San Antonio, 1995-96 (Box 616, Folder 19)
            - Washington
              - Seattle-King County, 1996 (Box 616, Folder 20)
              - Tacoma and Pierce County, 1996-97 (Box 616, Folder 21)
              - Walla Walla, 1996-97 (Box 616, Folder 22)
            - West Virginia: Wheeling, 1995-96 (Box 616, Folder 23)
            - Wisconsin
              - Green Bay-De Pere, 1996 (Box 616, Folder 24)
              - Christoph Memorial (Waukesha), 1995-97 (Box 616, Folder 25)
              - Wausau, 1996-97 (Box 616, Folder 26)
    - Publications
      - Health, general (Box 617)
        - Miscellaneous Pamphlets, n.d. (Box 617, Folder 1)
        - Beauty: miscellaneous pamphlets, 1936, 1946 (Box 617, Folder 2)
        - Change of Life: A Modern Woman's Guide by F.S. Edsall, 1949 (Box 617, Folder 3)
        - Every Girl's Health in Revue, Pantomime and Song, Volume I and II, compiled by Jane Bellows, 1924,25 (Box 617, Folder 4)
        - Feet and Shoes by Jane Bellows, 1928 (Box 617, Folder 5)
        - Health and Fitness brochures series, 1981 (Box 617, Folder 6)
        - Health and the Woman Movement by Clelia Duel Mosher, 1918 (Box 617, Folder 7)
        - Individual Exercises Illustrated by Jane Bellows, 1923 (Box 617, Folder 8)
        - Lady Be Fit! Exercises for Energy, Efficiency and Lasting Health by Dorothy Nye, 1942 (Box 617, Folder 9)
        - Nutrition: miscellaneous pamphlets, 1926-43 (Box 617, Folder 10)
        - A Symposium on Health and Recreation by Ten YWCA Leaders, 1936 (Box 618, Folder 1)
        - Woman's Physical Freedom by Clelia Duel Mosher, M.D., 1923 (Box 618, Folder 2)
        - Women After Forty: The Meaning of the Last Half of Life by Grace Loucks Elliot (Henry Holt & Co), 1936 (Box 618, Folder 3)
      - Administration
        - The Activities Ticket in a Health Education Program by Edith M. Gates, circa 1938 (Box 618, Folder 4)
        - A Community Health Program for the YWCA by Edith M. Gates, 1940 (Box 618, Folder 5)
        - The Department of Hygiene and Physical Education by Anna L. Brown, 1915 (Box 618, Folder 6)
        - The Health and Recreation Program in Clubs by Clara W. Alcroft, circa 1941 (Box 618, Folder 7)
        - The Health Education Committee by Edith M. Gates and Clara W. Alcroft, 1940, 1944 (Box 618, Folder 8)
        - The Health Education Council: What Is It? by Edith M. Gates, 1938 (Box 618, Folder 9)
        - Health Education Department Especially Adapted to City Associations, circa 1921 (Box 618, Folder 10)
        - Health Education Handbook
          - 1948, Section I-III (Box 618, Folder 11-14)
          - 1948, Section IV-V and 1951 revision (Box 619, Folder 1-3)
        - The Health Program in Small Associations by Edith M. Gates, 1936 (Box 619, Folder 4)
        - So You're Going to Do Publicity! A Publicity Primer in Terms of Health Education by Dorothy S. Cronan and Clara W. Alcroft, 1939, 1944 (Box 619, Folder 5)
        - The YWCA Health Program: A Program Guide for Leaders by Gladys L. Brown, 1965 (Box 619, Folder 6)
        - The YWCA Swimming Program: A Guide for Leaders, 1962 (Box 619, Folder 7)
      - Marriage and Family Life Education
        - General, 1945, 1948, n.d. (Box 619, Folder 8)
        - Education for Marriage Series: 1. First Steps in Program Building, No Date Has Been Set for the Wedding, and Working Wives, 1936-37 and 2. Marriages are Not Made in Heaven, 1939, 1947 revision by Janet Fowler Nelson and Margaret Hiller (Box 619, Folder 9-10)
        - Family Activities With Other Families: Needs and Interests of Different Ages by Helen Southard, 1959 (Box 619, Folder 11)
        - The Family-Covenant With Posterity by Grace Loucks Elliot, 1942 (Box 619, Folder 12)
        - The Human Venture in Sex, Love, and Marriage by Peter A. Bertocci, 1949 (Box 619, Folder 13)
        - Jobs and Marriage? Outlines for the Discussion of the Married Woman in Business by Grace L. Coyle, 1928 (Box 620, Folder 1)
        - Planning for Marriage: Outlines for Discussion by Young Men and Women by William Henry Morgan and Mildred Inskeep Morgan, 1943 (Box 620, Folder 2)
        - What Do You Think? Three Wartime Programs about ourselves, dates, wartime marriages, our fears today by Helen Southard, 1943 (Box 620, Folder 3)
        - What Our Marriage Means to Us by One Married Couple, 1939 (Box 620, Folder 4)
      - Mental Health
        - General, 1915, 1945, n.d. (Box 620, Folder 5)
        - Counseling in the YWCA by Tirzah Waite Anderson, 1946 (Box 620, Folder 6)
        - Have You Met Yourself?: A Psychological Introduction by Helen F. Southard, 1942 (Box 620, Folder 7)
        - Relaxation to the Rescue by Dorothy Nye and Josephine L. Rathbone, 1942 (Box 620, Folder 8)
        - To Your Health and Emotions, Lady! by Margaret W. Metcalf, 1948 (Box 620, Folder 9)
      - Sex Education
        - Miscellaneous pamphlets, 1943-70 (Box 620, Folder 10)
        - The Christian Approach to Social Morality by Richard C. Cabot, 1913 (Box 620, Folder 11)
        - Into the World by Victoria Emerson and James J. Thompson, 1950 (Box 620, Folder 12)
        - Planning for Sex Education, with particular reference to YWCA work with junior and senior high school students by Helen Southard, 1943 (Box 620, Folder 13)
        - The Sex Life of Youth by Grace Loucks Elliott and Harry Bone, ninth printing, 1947 (Box 621, Folder 1)
        - "Sex Morality Teaching Kit" including Sex Education Program: A Guide for Leaders by Helen Southard, 1965 (Box 621, Folder 2)
      - Recreation
        - General
          - Health Through Leisure Time Recreation by Edith M. Gates, 1931 (Box 621, Folder 3)
          - It Pays to Play by Mollie Heath Conn, 1940 (Box 621, Folder 4)
          - Partners in Play: Recreation for Young Men and Women Together by Mary J. Breen, 1934 (Box 621, Folder 5)
          - A Play Institute as given at Richmond, Virginia, Program Series no. XXIV, 1925 (Box 621, Folder 6)
          - Popularizing the Pool by Lucy South Proudfoot, 1924 (Box 621, Folder 7)
        - Arts and Crafts
          - The Arts: miscellaneous pamphlets, 1931?, 1945 (Box 621, Folder 8)
          - A Crafts Bulletin: of Equipment, Materials and Processes by Mary Dana and Ruth Perkins, 1936 (Box 621, Folder 9)
          - Crafts With Nature Materials by Lois Corke, circa 1942, 1946 (Box 621, Folder 10)
          - Creative Arts Kit, 1962, 1964 (Box 621, Folder 11)
          - Easy -to-Make Fashion Accessories by Janie W. Scott, 1953 (Box 621, Folder 12)
          - Flower Arrangement: A Hobby for All by Matilda Rogers, 1948 (Box 621, Folder 13)
          - Hand Book on the Use of Crafts by Ruth Perkins, 1934, 1936 (Box 622, Folder 1)
          - Nature Crafts by Emily A. Veazie, 1930 (Box 622, Folder 2)
          - Try It Yourself: An Introduction to the Arts (USO) by Florence C.E. Anderson, n.d. (Box 622, Folder 3)
        - Dance
          - Slavic Folk Dances compiled by Marjorie Crane Geary, 1924 (Box 622, Folder 4)
          - "Swing Your Ladies: Experiences with Country Dance in Co-ed Recreation," (No. X of the series Program Papers for Today and Tomorrow), compiled by Edith M. Gates, 1941 (Box 622, Folder 5)
          - Tap Dancing, 1930-1935 (Box 622, Folder 6)
        - Parties and Games
          - Birthday Parties for Boys and Girls From One to Fourteen by Mary Grosvenor Ellsworth, 1951 (Box 622, Folder 7)
          - The Fun Book: Stunts for Every Month in the Year by Edna Geister, 1923 (Box 622, Folder 8)
          - Holiday Parties by Dorothy Gladys Spicer, 1939 (Box 622, Folder 9)
          - Ice Breakers: Games and Stunts for Large and Small Groups by Edna Geister, 1918 (Box 623, Folder 1)
          - Ice-Breakers and the Ice-Breaker Herself by Edna Geister, 1921 (Box 623, Folder 2)
          - The Ice-Breaker Herself: Practical Suggestions for Recreation Leadership by Edna Geister, 1921 (Box 623, Folder 3)
          - It is To Laugh: A Book of Games and Stunts by Edna Geister, 1922 (Box 623, Folder 4)
          - Parties and Stunts Around the Year by Era Bentzer, 1924 (Box 623, Folder 5)
          - Parties for Young Americans by Dorothy Gladys Spicer, 1940 (Box 623, Folder 6)
          - Practical Parties by Ella Shannon Bowles, 1926 (Box 623, Folder 7)
          - Primer for Hostesses by Dorothy Sara, 1950 (Box 623, Folder 8)
          - Shower Parties for All Occasions by Helen Emily Webster, 1949 (Box 624, Folder 1)
          - Six Recreational Parties and Ten Recreational Parties by Helen Durham, 1924, n.d. (Box 624, Folder 2)
          - Special Parties and Stunts and Suggestions for Special Parties compiled by Era Betzner, circa 1923, n.d. (Box 624, Folder 3)
      - Serials
        - Health Education Bulletin, 1935-44 (Box 624, Folder 4-11)
        - HPER Newsletter, 1977-79 (Box 625, Folder 1)
        - Health Promotion/Sports Bulletin, 1990-92 (Box 625, Folder 2)
        - Playground: YWCA of the USA Health and Sports Update, 2000 (Box 625, Folder 3)
    - Reference Materials
      - Marriage and Family Life, 1906-61, n.d. (Box 625, Folder 4)
      - Recreation, 1920, 1930 (Box 625, Folder 5)
      - Sex education, 1929-89, n.d. (Box 625, Folder 6-7)
    - Training
      - General, 1920-86, n.d. (Box 625, Folder 8)
      - Health
        - HIV Prevention Through PACT, Mar 1992 (Box 625, Folder 9)
        - "Women as Preventors: An Adult-Teen Partnership" training package on alcohol abuse prevention, n.d. (Box 625, Folder 10)
      - Sex Education
        - Social Morality Institute, Feb-Mar 1915 (Box 625, Folder 11)
        - Dr. Mabel Ulrich's lectures at National YWCA, Jul 1915(?) (Box 625, Folder 12)
        - Social Morality, Mabel Ulrich, Jul 1917 (Box 625, Folder 13)
  - Subseries C. Music
    - General and History
      - "Historical Record of Music in the YWCA" (with documents) by Mary B. Wheeler, Jun 1966 (Box 626, Folder 1)
      - Articles re music and creative arts in the YWCA, 1938-70, n.d. (Box 626, Folder 2)
    - Committee and Staff
      - Biographies of Music Committee members, 1940-51, n.d. (Box 626, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1958-68 (Box 626, Folder 4)
        - Katharine B. Parker re establishment of Music Department, 1926-28 (Box 626, Folder 5)
        - Centennial music
          - General and local association songs, 1953-55 (Box 626, Folder 6)
          - Hymn in memory of Katherine B. Parker "O God of Every People" by John and Janet Harbison, 1953-55 (Box 626, Folder 7)
        - Controversial songs, 1955-58, n.d., [see also Correspondence re Sing Along the Way in publications section below] (Box 626, Folder 8)
        - Cooperative Recreation Service re printing of YWCA music, 1960-65 (Box 626, Folder 9)
        - Copyright, 1947-60, n.d.
          - General, 1947-60, n.d. (Box 626, Folder 10)
          - Song "Follow the Gleam," 1923-56 (Box 626, Folder 11-13)
          - Song "When a Y-Teen Girl Walks Down the Street," 1963 (Box 626, Folder 14)
          - Song "Witchcraft" by Margarett Snyder, 1949-65 (Box 626, Folder 15)
        - "Dakota Hymn," 1987 (Box 626, Folder 16)
        - National Federation of Music Clubs, National Music Week, 1955-68 (Box 626, Folder 17)
      - Minutes and reports
        - National Music Committee/National Music Subcommittee of the Division of Community YWCAs/National Music Subject Committee of the Program Subject Department, 1930-50 (Box 626, Folder 18-23)
        - Music Consultants' Meeting, 26 May 1966 (Box 627, Folder 1)
      - Audiovisual Mini-Kit, circa 1969 (Box 627, Folder 2)
      - Creative Arts
        - General reference, 1942-65, n.d. (Box 627, Folder 3)
        - In YWCA Program
          - Correspondence, 1961-62 (Box 627, Folder 4)
          - Articles, 1945-63 (Box 627, Folder 5)
          - Washington, DC, YWCA, 1950-61, n.d. (Box 627, Folder 6)
          - Creative Arts Kit, 1962 (Box 627, Folder 7)
          - Creative Arts Kit: correspondence, 1962-63 (Box 627, Folder 8)
          - Contemporary Programming Kit no. 3 "The Arts: How to Become Involved," 1968 (Box 627, Folder 9)
      - Questionnaire for Music and the Arts in the YWCA, Bureau of Research and Program Resources, 1969 (Box 627, Folder 10)
    - Conventions, Conferences, and other events
      - Conventions
        - 1946, 1949, 1952, 1955, 1958, 1961, 1964, 1967 (Box 627, Folder 11-20)
        - 1970, 1996 (Box 628, Folder 1-2)
      - YWCA of Canada National Convention, 1949-50 (Box 628, Folder 3)
      - Conferences
        - National Student Assembly, University of Illinois, Dec 1946-Jan 1947 (Box 628, Folder 4)
        - Business, Professional, and Industrial Council, Northwest Region, Feb 1947 (Box 628, Folder 5)
        - National Conference for Staff Working with Industrial Constituency, Mar 1947 (Box 628, Folder 6)
        - Summer Conferences, 1947 (Box 628, Folder 7)
        - YMCA-YWCA National Conference for High School Youth, Grinnell College, Jun 1947 (Box 628, Folder 8)
        - Business and Professional Fall Conference, Northern New England, Nov 1948 (Box 628, Folder 9)
        - Regional Conferences, 1948 (Box 628, Folder 10)
        - Summer Conferences, 1948 (Box 628, Folder 11)
        - Summer Conferences, 1949 (Box 628, Folder 12)
        - Eastern Regional, 1951 (Box 628, Folder 13)
        - Indiana Y-Teen Summer Conference, 1956 (Box 628, Folder 14)
        - Young Adult, 1960 (Box 628, Folder 15)
        - Southeastern Region, Jun 1960 (Box 628, Folder 16)
        - National Conference for Program Staff, Nov-Dec 1960 (Box 628, Folder 17)
        - Y-Teen Round Table, 1 Apr 1963 (Box 628, Folder 18)
        - National Y-Teen Conference, Washington, DC, Aug 1965 (Box 628, Folder 19)
      - Business and Professional Nationwide Observance Day, 1943 (Box 628, Folder 20)
      - National Industrial Assembly, 1936 (Box 628, Folder 21)
      - National Staff Assembly and other gatherings at "600," 1928-58, n.d. (Box 628, Folder 22)
      - National YWCA Cycle Meeting, Mar 1968 (Box 628, Folder 23)
      - Summer Camp Program, 1957-65 (Box 628, Folder 24)
    - Projects
      - "Back the Beginners" a world fellowship project for young adults, 1957-58 (Box 628, Folder 25)
      - Y-Teen Creative Arts Project '69: correspondence and notes, 1968-69 (Box 628, Folder 26)
      - Y-Teen Folk Song Project
        - Correspondence, minutes, notes, reports, 1964-66 (Box 628, Folder 27)
        - Permissions correspondence, 1966 (Box 628, Folder 28)
        - Music and lyrics, 1965-66 (Box 628, Folder 29)
      - Cleveland YWCA "World Symphony" program, n.d. (Box 628, Folder 30)
      - Lancaster (PA) YWCA Vivaldi Orchestra program, 1966 (Box 628, Folder 31)
      - New York City YWCA, Clark Center for the Performing Arts, 1964-65 (Box 629, Folder 1)
      - Philadelphia YWCA "Singing City" and Seven Arts Series, 1962-66 (Box 629, Folder 2)
      - San Francisco Song Festival, 1964 (Box 629, Folder 3)
      - Topeka Y-Teen Clubs "Sing a Song of Friendship," Jan 1948 (Box 629, Folder 4)
    - Publications
      - Bibliographies
        - General, 1929-43(?) (Box 629, Folder 5)
        - "A Music Bibliography for Association Leaders," Laboratory Division, 1936, 1938, 1939 (Box 629, Folder 6)
        - "Music for a Student Christian Movement: Suggestions for 1935" and "Music for a Student Christian Movement," National Student Council of the YWCA, 1935-36, n.d. (Box 629, Folder 7)
        - "Music Resources for Worship Planning" by Marion Peabody, TWP, 1937 (Box 629, Folder 8)
        - Music Suggestions for the Christmas Season Selected from Many Sources by Marion Peabody, The Womans Press, 1934 (Box 629, Folder 9)
      - Program and training materials
        - The American Indians and Their Music by Frances Densmore, 1936 (Box 629, Folder 10)
        - "Club Music" leaflet, 1930 (Box 629, Folder 11)
        - Conference Leaders Handbook, Music section, 1958 (Box 629, Folder 12)
        - "Criteria for Song Leaders," circa 1940s (Box 629, Folder 13)
        - Let's Have Music edited by Marie Oliver, The Womans Press, 1945; second edition, 1948 (Box 629, Folder 14)
        - "The Music Committee-Its Place and Task in the Association," pamphlet produced by the Laboratory Division: correspondence and pamphlet, 1933-35 (Box 629, Folder 15)
        - "Music in YWCA Conferences" by Martha Ramsey, circa 1938 (Box 629, Folder 16)
        - Music in the YWCA: A Guide to Program Planning by Elizabeth Lawson, The Womans Press, 1934 (Box 629, Folder 17)
        - Music, Let's Have More of It, pamphlet and correspondence, 1960 (Box 629, Folder 18)
        - "Notes for the Conference Song Leader," leaflets, 1964-69 (Box 629, Folder 19)
        - Program Packets, 1945-47 (Box 629, Folder 20)
      - Songbooks and Hymnals
        - Miscellaneous, circa 1913-36 (Box 629, Folder 21)
        - The American Songbag, 1930, n.d. (Box 629, Folder 22)
        - The Association Hymnal, TWP
          - 1924 (Box 629, Folder 23)
          - 1926 (Box 630, Folder 1)
        - Association Music, circa 1915, circa 1920, n.d. (Box 630, Folder 2)
        - Christmas and New Year Songs compiled by Florence H. Botsford, The Womans Press, 1922 (Box 630, Folder 3)
        - Convention, 1932, 1934, 1940, 1970 (Box 630, Folder 4)
        - Folk Songs of Many Peoples with English Versions by American Poets compiled and edited by Florence Hudson Botsford, TWP
          - Vol I, 1921 (Box 630, Folder 5)
          - Vol. II, 1922 (Box 630, Folder 6)
        - Folk Songs of Poland reprinted from Vol. I of Folk Songs of Many Peoples, TWP, 1922 (Box 631, Folder 1)
        - Hymns edited by the Music Subcommittee of the National Board of the YWCAs, TWP, [1945?] (Box 631, Folder 2)
        - International Training Institute Songbook, 1969
          - Correspondence, 1969, n.d. (Box 631, Folder 3)
          - Manuscript and photocopies, 1969 (Box 631, Folder 4)
        - A Little Carol Book: Carols From Ten Countries, TWP, n.d. (Box 631, Folder 5)
        - Our Student Movement Sings/Our Student Movements Sing, 1955, n.d. (Box 631, Folder 6)
        - Sing Along the Way/Sing Along
          - circa 1943-65 (Box 631, Folder 7-10)
          - Accompaniments, Jul and Oct 1950 and Jan 1955 (Box 632, Folder 1)
          - Correspondence
            - General and notes, 1950-70, n.d. (Box 632, Folder 2-4)
            - Re controversial songs, 1943-60, n.d. (Box 632, Folder 5)
            - Re accompaniment book, 1950 (Box 632, Folder 6)
          - "Notes for Song Leaders," Jun 1965 (Box 632, Folder 7)
          - "On Playing the Autoharp Accompaniments in 'Sing Along'": correspondence, notes, and text, 1957-58 (Box 632, Folder 8)
          - Phonograph recording "Sing Along": correspondence, 1960-63 (Box 632, Folder 9)
        - Sing Around the World Songs, The Womans Press, 1923 (Box 632, Folder 10)
        - The Song Book of the Y.W.C.A. compiled by Imogene B. Ireland, TWP, 1926 (Box 632, Folder 11)
        - Songs for Freedom edited by the Music Subcommittee of the National Board, The Womans Press, circa 1946 (Box 632, Folder 12)
        - Songs, Rounds and Carols, The Womans Press, 1940 (Box 632, Folder 13)
        - Songs, Rounds and Graces, The Womans Press, 1935 (Box 632, Folder 14)
        - Girl Reserve/Y-Teen
          - Girl Reserve Song-Book
            - 1923-27 and supplement (Box 632, Folder 15-16)
            - 1941 (Box 633, Folder 1)
          - Y-Teen Song Book, 1946 (Box 633, Folder 2)
          - Youth Sings, YMCA-YWCA National Conference for High School Youth, 1947 (Box 633, Folder 3)
    - YWCA Songs and Song Sheets
      - Miscellaneous, 1916, 1938, n.d. (Box 633, Folder 4)
      - "A Christmas Carol from Jamaica" composed by YWCA members,circa 1949 (Box 633, Folder 5)
      - Centennial Hymn, "O God of Every People" by John and Janet Harbison, 1955 (Box 633, Folder 6)
      - Centennial songs written by members of local associations, 1953-55 (Box 633, Folder 7)
      - Descant for "Goodnight Beloved" by Lucy Shulte and Marie Oliver, n.d. (Box 633, Folder 8)
      - "Follow the Gleam" 1923, 1958-62 (Box 633, Folder 9)
      - Girl Reserve and Y-Teen songs, 1935-58, n.d. (Box 633, Folder 10)
      - "Our Song" Y-Teen song, 1947-48 (Box 633, Folder 11)
      - Silver Bay Conference songs, 1920-35 (Box 633, Folder 12)
      - Songs by Lucy Shulte and Louise Schooler, 1944 (Box 633, Folder 13)
      - 'Tis Not by Might,' World YWCA Motto, music by Frederich Flemming (Box 633, Folder 14)
      - YWCA Purpose
        - Music by Wanda Canny, circa 1965 (Box 633, Folder 15)
        - Music by Mary E. Swain, circa 1955 (Box 633, Folder 16)
      - Y-Teen Hymn by Clara Ellen Shipman, n.d. (Box 633, Folder 17)
    - Reference files, General
      - General, 1929-50, n.d. (Box 633, Folder 18)
      - African music, dance, drama, 19950-62, n.d. (Box 633, Folder 19)
      - Amateur Chamber Music Players, 1956, n.d. (Box 633, Folder 20)
      - American Indian music, 1964-65 (Box 633, Folder 21)
      - Arab music, 1958, 1960 (Box 633, Folder 22)
      - British YWCA music, 1946 (Box 633, Folder 23)
      - Children and families, 1934-64, n.d. (Box 633, Folder 24)
      - Chinese music, 1933, n.d. (Box 633, Folder 25)
      - Choral music for women's voices, 1945, 1966-67 (Box 633, Folder 26)
      - Christmas music and program, 1931-79, n.d. (Box 633, Folder 27)
      - Church music, workshop at Union Theological Seminary, 1969 (Box 634, Folder 1)
      - Civil Rights, music in movement, 1962-65, n.d. (Box 634, Folder 2)
      - Copyright law, 1942-64, n.d. (Box 634, Folder 3)
      - Finnish music and dance, 1941, n.d. (Box 634, Folder 4)
      - Folk music, 1933-65, n.d. (Box 634, Folder 5-8)
      - Hymns, 1924-66, n.d. (Box 634, Folder 9)
      - Indian music, 1936, n.d. (Box 634, Folder 10)
      - Instruments
        - Hand made, 1936-58 (Box 634, Folder 11)
        - Recorders, 1942-47, n.d. (Box 634, Folder 12)
        - Rhythm band/toy symphony, 1930-60, n.d. (Box 634, Folder 13)
        - Shepherd's pipes, 1935-50, n.d. (Box 634, Folder 14)